Guide to the Western Connecticut State University Photographs and Miscellanea RG 8
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
- Series II: WCSU Realia, 45475
  - Alumni, 45532
    - Realia, 45533
      - DTC and DSC Beanie Box, 1942-1961; 45541 (Box Realia_OS 3, Item *)
        DTC Mortimer Johnson beanie
        DSC Arata beanie
        DTC Donovan beanie
        DTC freshman beanie
        Marjorie Byiteck Salem beanie ('65, m '76)
      - John R Perkins memorabilia, 1890-1920; 45540 (Box Realia_OS 4, Item *)
        Framed John R Perkins Sr b/w photo
        Family ancestry "Ancestors of 13* Shannon Elizabeth" of Perkins
        John R Perkins 1892 b/w photo Washington, CT
      - Menegay '53 Textiles, 1953; 45539 (Box Realia_OS 5, Item *)
        Gym suit and beanie
      - Portrait of Unidentified Woman, ca.1955; 45538 (Box Realia_OS 6, Item *)
        Oil on canvas. The portrait is thought to be of a DTC student.
      - Varsity Letters and patches, 1944-1959; 45537 (Box Realia_OS 8, Item *)
        DTC Varsity Letters x 2, DTC Blazer patch (Betty Ann Smith, '48), DTC Varsity letter (large) Robert J. Brayton, '55.
      - WCSU Alumni Association miscellanea, 1980-2007; 45536 (Box Realia_08.1, Item *)
        WCSU Police patch x4
        WCSU alumni hat
        WCSU centennial hat
        WCSU decal
        WCSU 6'" ruler
        WCSU leather bookmark x2
        WCSU alumni assoc. photo holder key fob
        WCSU pencil
        WCSU alumni assoc. key fob
        WCSU clip bookmark
        Danbury American Revolution Bicentennial commemorative coin
        WCSU alumni association decal x2
        O'Neill Center Ribbon Cutting Commemorative ceramic coffee mug x2
        Navy blue WCSU Commemorative ceramic coffee mug
        WCSU PAC lanyard
        '"Shalamazoo at Venue 21'" event momento
        Ruth A Haas Library dedication momento Clock
        WCSU glass paperweight
        1999 Commencement Invitation/picture frame
        1968, 1969 & 1970 Class reunion invitation/picture frame
        "You Belong in CT" pin
        WCSU 1984-1985 Women's Basketball commemorative T-shirt
        Campus-to-Campus 5k Road Race T-shirt x2
        Campus-to-Campus 5k Road Race T-shirt
        1996 PAC and Alumni Association homecoming "Western hoe-down" scarf
        Haas Library Project T-shirt
        PAC fall 1997 movie schedule bookmark
        America's Top 100 Banned Books Postcard's x3
        Centennial banner x3
        WCSU SGA bumpersticker (1983)x2
        Red WCSU Spring Weekend Chalice/Goblet, 1971
        2 President J.W. Schmotter Inauguration Tote bags
        2 Athletic Hall of Fame paper weights
        1 WCSU at Waterbury paper weight; 1 WCSU Centennital paperweight
      - Pins "Catch the Western Spirit" Homecoming Week Oct. 13-18, 2008; 45535 (Box Realia_08.1, Item *)
      - Pins and button, 1906-1959; 45534 (Box Realia_US 1, Item 1-4)
        KEEP TUITION DOWN' button
        DNS, DTC Graduation pins x 3 Western Connecticut State University pin circa 2000
      - Autographed DTC Baseballs, 1952-1954 (Box Realia_US 2, Item a-b)
        The baseballs were donated by Robert J. Brayton who played on the baseball team at Danbury State Teacher's College. Accompanying the baseballs are two notes from Brayton re: the origin and significance along with a note to Brayton from classmate Herman Anderson.
      - 1969 Football Team Clippings, 50465 (Box Realia_OS 1)
      - Florence Louise Anderson scrapbook, 1928-1929 (Box realia_13, Item 43)
        Scrapbook cover and pages. Images and many inserts removed for preservation. See folders for contents.
      - Florence Anderson scrapbook (photos), 1928-1929 (Box realia_13, Folder 1)
      - Florence Anderson scrapbook (inserts), 1928-1929 (Box realia_13, Folder 2-3)
        Contains theater programs, report cards, notes, newsletters, and ephemera.
  - Art, 45507
    - Commemerative, 45517
      - Framed photo 10 students w/awards and Nathan Ansell, [1980s?]; 45531 (Item 5.1)
      - Photo of Main Street Danbury, 1870; 45530 (Item 5.2)
        Framed print from Scott Fanton Museum collection.
      - President Hoover's "The Children's Charter", ca.1945; 45529 (Item 6)
      - Framed "Statement of Support for the Guard & Reserve" from the Dept. of Defense, signed by R Haas, 1974; 45528 (Item 7)
      - Framed Delta Kappa Phi Charter, 1968; 45527 (Item 8)
      - Framed drawing of R. Haas Library, 1991; 45526 (Item 9)
      - Gangal VII, 1969; 45525 (Item 10)
      - Framed portrait of original Haas library with student life, 1990s; 45524 (Item 11)
      - Framed WCSU panel calendar, 1991-1992; 45523 (Item 12)
      - Large Hanging maps, undated; 45522 (Item 13)
        Fairfield county x2, CT x1
      - Miscellaneous Plaques, 1950-2012; 45521 (Item 14-22)
        National Exchange Club 1950s; WCSU Faculty Emeriti Distinguished Service Tribute 1990-91; Mayor's Ball Service Award 2004 2006, 2007; Danbury Housing Partnership award 2011; Women's Center 2012; India Association of Greater Danbury 2008
      - Exchange Club framed replicas of famous American Documents, undated; 45518 (Item 1-5)
        Monroe Doctrine
        The Northwest Ordinance
        The Gettysburg Address
        The Emancipation Proclomation
        Jackson's Letter Describing New Orleans
      - Midnight Northeastern on Bass Rocks, 1981 (Item 42)
        Large 8 x 4ft oil on canvas - framed. By Patricia Yaps (Holcomb) and Terry Verrilli. Presented in honor of Ruth Haas to Western Connecticut State College by John Stetson and Fred Fearn, Danbury Fair Arts and Crafts.
    - Decorative, 45508
      - Medieval Gradual Manuscript Leaf, psalm 102 or 103, undated; 45516 (Folder OS Folder 1.1, Item 1)
        One single half of a folio page. A Gregorian manuscript of psalm 102 or 103 marking Michaelmas with music (5 line staff) on lamb or sheep skin. It strongly resemples Spanish manuscripts from the late 1500s. Provenance is unknown.
      - Art department student paintings for library, 1990s; 45515 (Item 14.1, Item 1-9)
        Oil on canvas panels: Albert Einstein By Karin Walko; Mark Twain By Pam Sundlof; William Shakespeare By Vartan Yeranos; Ansel Adams By Marlana Cole; Georgia O'Keeffe By Doreen Negri; Andy Warhol By Heather Scott; Salvador Dali By Vanda Janson; Mother Teresa By Beth Mccormack; Isaac Asimov By Inga Olson
      - Needlepoint of Connecticut State Seal, 1976; 45514 (Item 26)
        needlework done by Phyllis Nathanson
      - Framed aerial photograph of Danbury, 1929; 45513 (Item 27)
        48 x 48" under glass.
      - [Frog], painting, framed; Jim Timmins, 1970s; 45512 (Item 28)
        Transferred from former director of library - Ralph Hollibaugh's office
      - Framed topographical map of Connecticut, 1990; 45511 (Item 29)
        ~24x36" color map. US Geological Survey.
      - Needlepoint replica of Gilbert Stewart painting of George Washington, 1960s; 45510 (Item 30)
        This needlepoint portrait of George Washington is a copy of Gilbert Stewart's "Lansdowne" portrait which was the portrait Dolley Madison saved from the British during the War of 1812. This reproduction was made in 1840 by Mrs Emily Keach of Sandy Hill, NY and took her over 12 months to complete. Mrs. Keach gave this portrait to Thomas Blackman Wheeler (her daughter's husband) who in turn passed it on to his son Henry Wheeler. Henry Wheeler's daughter, Marguerite Wheeler Patchen, was a teacher in the laboratory school of WestConn, and after inheriting the portrait from her Father, donated it with her sister (Annie O. Wheeler) to the College on September 1, 1969.
      - Portrait of unidentified child in sailor's cap, ca.1918; 45509 (Item 32)
        Portrait appears to be oil paint on canvass. The canvass is mounted in a wooden frame with gold painted highlights. The boy pictured is wearing a sailor's cap which has on its band "Bridgeport." The USS Bridgeport was a German built ship that was seized by the US Navy in 1917 and used as a destroyer in World War I. On the reverse side of the canvass "Richard" is written in pencil in large letters.
      - [Alice seated pose], sculpture by Herbert Hofmann-Ysenbourg, 1960s; 57708 (Item 32.5)
        Immediate Source of Acquisition
        Piece had been in the director's conference room in the Haas Library. Brought to the Archives in August of 2013. Piece was presumably donated by WCSU Professor, Al Stewart
      - Rhys Caparn sculptures, 1957-1978; 58955 (Item 32.6 - 32.8)
        Donated to the Haas Library by the artist in 1985.
      - Automotem Totem by Jim Timmins, 1965-1975 (Item 33)
        On display in WCSU Archives Connecticut Room.
      - Henry David Thoreau, nail collage, by Jim Timmins, 1965-1975 (Item 34)
        On Display in WCSU Archives Connecticut Room
        Gift of Richard J. Gerber
      - [Fisherman on the shore], by John C. Pellew, watercolor, ca. 1975 (Folder OS Folder 3, Item 35)
      - Chagall Pint, circa 1960 (Folder OS Folder 3, Item 44)
  - Historic Publications, 45502
    - History WCSC, 1903-1978, 45506 (Box Realia_04, Folder 5)
      x2
    - A History of Western Connecticut State University, 1978-1993, 1878-1993 (Box Realia_04, Folder 5.1)
    - School Viewbooks, DSTC Brochure, ca. 1945-1959; 45505 (Box Realia_04, Folder 6)
      x3
    - Student Handbooks, 1949-1950; 45504 (Box Realia_04, Folder 7)
      SGA handbook, student handbook 1949-1950, college union handbook
    - Campus Informational Materials, 1960 - ca. 1990 (Box Realia_04, Folder 7.1)
    - Jack Sikora Soc. 100 Custom Course Packet, 1997 (Box Realia_04, Folder 7.2)
    - Fairfield Hall Renovation Event Program, 2008; 45503 (Box Realia_04, Folder 8)
      Fairfield Hall Memories and Fairfield Hall Recollections, by Darla Shaw. Incl. Fairfield Hall history.
    - Invitation to President Clinton visit Celebration, 2005-10-03 (Box Realia_04, Folder 9)
      President Bill Clinton came to WCSU to thank the students of Connecticut for their generous contributions towards building a 1500 pupil school in Sri Lanka.
    - Parking Brochure, 1988 (Box Realia_04, Folder 10)
      Brochure issued by University Police, includes parking rules and regulations and parking maps for both Midtown and Westside campuses.
    - Dedication Programs, 2000 (Box Realia_04, Folder 11)
      Ruth Haas Lirary Dedication October 17, 2000 Truman A. Warner Hall Dedication October 27, 2000
  - Plans, 45490
    - Young Library floor Plan - Stephen L. Griss architect, 1982-03-01 (Folder OS Folder 1, Item 1)
    - Haas - Library Plans, 1999; 45500 (Folder OS Folder 1, Item 2)
      Book of blueprints with 2 copies of lighting plan.
    - Haas - Warner Hall/Swing Space for Haas Library, 1997; 45501 (Folder OS Folder 2)
    - White Street Master Plan, 1987 (Folder OS Folder 1.3)
      10 plans for midtown campus renovations.
    - Haas Library Building Contract Bid, 1997; 45499 (Box Realia_08, Folder 1)
      Bound Copy of "Vol. 1 of 3 Specification Contract No. BI-RD-103/103A Ruth A. Haas Library Edition and Swing Building" June 1997
    - Haas Library Renovations General Information and Correspondence, undated; 45498 (Box Realia_08, Folder 2)
    - Haas Library Renovations Construction Reports, 1998-2000; 45497 (Box Realia_08, Folder 3)
      May 1998, May 2000, Monthly Employment and Utilization Reports
    - Haas Library Renovations Construction Reports, 2000; 45496 (Box Realia_08, Folder 4)
      June 2000 Monthly Employment and Utilization Reports
    - Haas Library Renovations Construction Reports, 2000; 45495 (Box Realia_08, Folder 5)
      July 2000 Monthly Employment and Utilization Reports
    - Haas Library Renovations Contruction Reports, 2000; 45494 (Box Realia_08, Folder 6)
      August 2000 Monthly Employment and Utilization Reports
    - Haas Library Renovations Construction Daily Diaries, 2000; 45493 (Box Realia_08, Folder 7)
      January - February 2000, Dept. of Public Works
    - Haas Library Renovations Contruction Daily Diaries, 2000; 45492 (Box Realia_08, Folder 8)
      March - April 2000, Dept. of Public Works
    - Haas Library Renovations Contruction Daily Diaries, 2000; 45491 (Box Realia_08, Folder 9)
      May - June 2000, Dept. of Public Works
    - Stadium Seating and Press Box Study, Friar Associates, 2001 (Box Realia_OS 1)
  - Student Work, 1962-1970; 49851
    Scope and Contents
    This subseries is made up of 98 student papers. The general theme to most of these papers tends to focus on either the Danbury area or Connecticut in general, but there are some exceptions. There are several papers that contain photos, maps, and other extra material. Many of these papers were done for Dr. Truman Warner's classes.
    Most of these papers have complete identifying information including the student's name, paper title, the class for which the paper was done, the professor, and the date. However, not all the papers contain all this information. There were seven papers to which the identity of the student was either in question or not known at all. Some papers have some pages missing. It should also be noted that this collection originally had 101 student papers, but three are now missing. This collection was originally a part of Acc. #100 with each numbered from 1-101.
    The papers are arranged alphabetically by the student's last name with the unknown papers appearing at the end. In cases in which the student had more than one paper in the collection, the arrangement goes alphabetically by the title of their paper.
    Biographical / Historical
    The papers were written primarily for history classes, but few were written for social science classes. Dates of these papers range from as early as 1962 and go up to 1970, although most of the papers fall in between 1967-1970.
    Many of these papers appear to have been done for research seminar classes, although it seems that not all were done for that particular reason.
    - Allen, Dorothy C., "Process and Machinery Used in Making a Man's Fur Felt Hat: 1860s and 1920s," History, May 15, 1968, 111 pgs. (w/ photos) (Pages 69-71 are missing), 49852 (Box Realia_09, Folder 1-2)
    - Allen, Dorothy C., "Transportation Development to 1850 And Initial Controversy Over Railroading," History, January 15, 1968, 48 pgs., 49853 (Box Realia_09, Folder 3)
    - Bahan, Madeline, "Entertainment in Danbury, 1865-1880," History (Dr. Truman Warner), January 30, 1966, 58 pgs., 49854 (Box Realia_09, Folder 4)
    - Barlow, Alfred G., "The Danbury Hatting Unions 1880- 1902," History (Mr. L. Dente), June 1, 1967, 98 pgs., 49855 (Box Realia_09, Folder 5)
    - Benefiel, Rodger C., "Title II, The Narcotic Addict Rehabilitation Act of 1966: Its Development, Implementation and Evaluation," Social Science, fall 1969, 69 pgs., 49856 (Box Realia_09, Folder 6)
    - Benison, Terry, "The Jew in the 1900s in Danbury: The Coming About of the United Jewish Center," History, 15 pgs., undated; 49857 (Box Realia_09, Folder 7)
    - Bernstein, Floyd B, "The Story of the Thirteenth Infantry Regiment of Connecticut Volunteers as Seen by One Everett S. Dubar," History (Dr. Truman Warner), 1969-1970, 51 pgs., 49858 (Box Realia_09, Folder 8)
    - Brogan, Daniel T., "The Attitudes Toward the United States Neutrality in Bridgeport, Connecticut, as Compared to the Nation 1914-1917," History, 1970, 50 pgs., 49859 (Box Realia_09, Folder 9)
    - Butterly Jr., William, "The Newspapers of Waterbury: A History," History (Dr. Truman Warner), May 1967, 48 pgs., 49860 (Box Realia_09, Folder 10)
    - Butterly Jr., William, "Protestants and Catholics in Watertown," History, March 26, 1969, 38 pgs. (w/maps), 49861 (Box Realia_09, Folder 11)
    - Byrnes, David M., "The Effect of an Institution on a Small Town Society: To What Degree Did the Kent School Affect the Economic, Political, Social, and Cultural Development of the Town of Kent in 1967," History (Mr. David Detzer), January 19, 1967, 24 pgs., 49862 (Box Realia_09, Folder 12)
    - Clark, William J., "Roads and Highways in the Danbury Area During the Revolutionary Era," History (Dr. Truman Warner), 46 pgs. (w/maps), undated; 49863 (Box Realia_09, Folder 13)
    - Coelho Jr., Anthony M., "The Portuguese of Danbury: A Case Study," Social Science, 59 pgs. (w/ photos and maps), undated; 49864 (Box Realia_09, Folder 14)
    - Connolly, Martin T., "Scarsdale's Non-Partisan Government," Social Science, June 1967, 69 pgs., 49865 (Box Realia_09, Folder 15)
    - Connolly, Martin T., "White Plains, New York: Its Governmental Structure to 1915 and How It Developed," History (Dr. Truman Warner), February 12, 1967, 35 pgs., 49866 (Box Realia_09, Folder 16)
    - Cordone, Angelo, "Early Temperance Movements in Litchfield, Connecticut, and Dr. Lyman Beecher," History (Dr. Truman Warner), January 1968, 32 pgs., undated; 49867 (Box Realia_09, Folder 17)
    - Dagostine Jr., Louis, "Expanding the Boys Club Program in Shelton-Derby, Conn.," Social Science (Dr. Thomas Godward), May 27, 1965, 72 pgs., 49868 (Box Realia_09, Folder 18)
    - Dahncke, Bob, "Key to the Continent: The Hudson Highlands and the Putnam Area During the Revolutionary War," History, November 12, 1964, 20 pgs., 49869 (Box Realia_09, Folder 19)
    - Dilluvio, Anthony V. "The Establishment & Growth of the Railroads in Danbury During the 19th Century," (Rough Draft), History, 13 pgs. (w/maps), undated; 49870 (Box Realia_09, Folder 20)
    - Doyle, George, "The Rise and Fall of the Foreign Mission School at Cornwall, Connecticut," History (Dr. Truman Warner), 1962, 65 pgs., 49871 (Box Realia_09, Folder 21)
    - Doyle, George F., "The Abolitionist Movement in Connecticut," History (Dr. Truman Warner), 26 pgs. (w/map), undated; 49872 (Box Realia_09, Folder 22)
    - Doyle, Robert, "The Immigrants Who Came to Danbury Between the Years 1805-1914," History (Dr. Truman Warner), February 10, 1964, 34 pgs., 49873 (Box Realia_09, Folder 23)
    - Doyle, Robert, "The Story of Methodism and History of the Long Ridge Methodist Episcopal Church 1820-1910," History, May 1966, 75 pgs. (w/photos), 49874 (Box Realia_09, Folder 24)
    - Engel, Peck, "The New York-Connecticut Boundary," History (Dr. Truman Warner), 30 pgs. (w/ maps), undated; 49875 (Box Realia_09, Folder 25)
    - Engel, Peck B.,"Germany, The Long Road to the League: The Problem of Germany's Entry into the League of Nations in 1926," History (Dr. Eric Roman), March 17, 1970, 64 pgs., 49876 (Box Realia_09, Folder 26)
    - Fernandez, Lynn H. "A History of Lake Candlewood," History (Dr. Truman Warner), January 1967, 95 pgs. (w/maps and illustrations), one of two, 49877 (Box Realia_09, Folder 27)
    - Fernandez, Lynn H. "A History of Lake Candlewood," History (Dr. Truman Warner), January 1967, 95 pgs. (w/maps and illustrations), two of two, 49878 (Box Realia_09, Folder 28)
    - Ferrara, Randall P., "A History of the Congregational Church of Stamford: With the Purpose of Offering an Example of an Average New England Congregational Church 1635-1775," History, 102 pgs., undated; 49879 (Box Realia_09, Folder 29)
    - Flanagan, Michael, "The Town of Carmel and the Ruppert Brewery," History, 48 pgs. (w/map), undated; 49880 (Box Realia_09, Folder 30)
    - Foley, William, "Development of Fire Protection in the City of Danbury During the 19th Century," (First Draft), History (Dr. Martha Counts), November 12, 1964, 21 pgs., 49881 (Box Realia_09, Folder 31)
    - Forbes, Linda, "History of the Bethel Church and the Ecclesiastical Society: 1759-1798," History, May 15, 1967, 97 pgs., 49882 (Box Realia_09, Folder 33)
    - Gazek, Richard C., "The Sandemanian Religion," History (Dr. Truman Warner), February 1967, 36 pgs., 49883 (Box Realia_09, Folder 33)
    - Glass, Thomas R. H., "The Structure and the Responsibility of the Borough of Danbury, 1822-1845," History (Dr. Truman Warner), June 1, 1967, 41 pgs., 49884 (Box Realia_09, Folder 34)
    - Glass, Thomas Randall Hooker, "Who Governed in Danbury? 1820-1875," History (Dr. Thomas Kelso), May 1968, 45 pgs., 49885 (Box Realia_09, Folder 35)
    - Geel, William, "Danbury Involvement in World War I," History, April 28, 1970, 30 pgs., 49886 (Box Realia_09, Folder 36)
    - Guastaferri, Nina, "Attitudes of Brookfield Townspeople on Decisions Made by the Town," Social Science (Dr. Thomas Godward), 38 pgs., undated; 49887 (Box Realia_09, Folder 37)
    - Guastaferri, Nina, "Company C of the 17th Connecticut Regiment and Its Experience in the Civil War," History (Dr. Truman Warner), May 1968, 101 pgs (w/maps and illustrations), 49888 (Box Realia_09, Folder 38-39)
    - Hammond, Gladys, "Pocket Letter Book 1851," History, 5pgs. (3 copies), undated; 49889 (Box Realia_09, Folder 40)
    - Hammond, Gladys B, "Broadview Farm 1869-1962 Danbury, Connecticut," History (Dr. Martha Counts), May 21, 1965, 99 pgs. (w/photos and maps), 49890 (Box Realia_09, Folder 41-42)
    - Hammond, Gladys B., "The Development of Social Welfare in Danbury, Connecticut, During the Period 1850-1900," History and Social Science (Dr. Truman Warner and Dr. Martha Counts) 1964, 31 pgs., 49891 (Box Realia_09, Folder 43)
    - Hawkins, Robert L., "The Attitude of Danburians During the Civil War," History (Dr. Truman Warner), 1970, 58 pgs., 49892 (Box Realia_09, Folder 44)
    - Henley, Joan K., "How a Community Gets a Hospital," Social Science (Dr. Thomas Godward), May 18, 1965, 120 pgs., 49893 (Box Realia_09, Folder 45-46)
    - Heron, D., "The Establishment of Danbury Normal School," History (Mr. David Detzer), 31 pgs, undated; 49894 (Box Realia_09, Folder 47)
    - Hibbert, Roger, "1850-1900 Labor Management Relations in the Hatting Industry in Danbury," History, 15 pgs., undated; 49895 (Box Realia_09, Folder 48)
    - Jacob, Barbara L., "Prohibition in Danbury, Connecticut," History (Dr. Truman Warner), 19 pgs., undated; 49896 (Box Realia_09, Folder 49)
    - Jukich, Ruth M., "The Peekskill Riots," History (Dr. Truman Warner), fall 1967, 92 pgs, undated; 49897 (Box Realia_09, Folder 50)
    - Keenan, Michael J., "Preliminary Report Danbury School Systems 1796-1873," History, 25 pgs (w/ charts), undated; 49898 (Box Realia_09, Folder 51)
    - 52-53 Keenan, Michael John, "The Development of the 963rd Field Artillery Battalion from the Colonial Militia to the Nuclear Age Connecticut National Guard," History, April 1966, 128 pgs., 49899 (Box Realia_09, Folder 52-53)
    - Kelly Jr., Joseph E., "Growth and Development of Hatting Unions in Danbury, Conn., 1800-1896," History, January 11, 1967, 41 pgs., 49900 (Box Realia_09, Folder 54)
    - Kirk, Abby, "An Exploratory Study of the Work Release Program at the Federal Correctional Institution at Danbury, Connecticut," Social Science, June 2, 1967, 49 pgs., 49901 (Box Realia_09, Folder 55)
    - Knowlton, Eric L., "Iron Mining in Northwestern Connecticut 1731-1925: A Study of the Effects of Extracting and Processing Ore in Five Communities," History, 1967, 71 pgs., 49902 (Box Realia_09, Folder 56)
    - Knox, Jane, "The Economic Development of Ridgefield, Connecticut, 1800-1820," History, June 1967, 40 pgs., 49903 (Box Realia_09, Folder 57)
    - Knox, Jane, "Life in Ridgefield, Connecticut, During the 1850s as Viewed by a Young Girl and a Man of the World," History, May 15, 1968, 129 pgs., 49904 (Box Realia_09, Folder 58-59)
    - Kolwicz, James, "Employment for Danbury Area High School Graduates," Social Science, May 1965, 49 pgs., 49905 (Box Realia_09, Folder 60)
    - Leary, Karen A, "James White Nichols," History (Dr. Truman Warner), 27 pgs., undated; 49906 (Box Realia_09, Folder 61)
    - Leslie, G. R., "Ridgefield, Connecticut, 1770-1785: A Study of the Effect of the American Revolution in One Community," History, 1966, 349 pgs., undated; 49907 (Box Realia_10, Folder 62-65)
    - Lovallo, Vincent, "Danbury (Western Conn.) and the War of 1812," History (Dr. Martha Counts), 18 pgs., undated; 49908 (Box Realia_10, Folder 66)